(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-03T05:20:57.391210",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ふふっ、すごーい！不知火フレアだよ！
"Hahaha... Wow, it's Shiranui Flare!"
みんなと、見てるかな？
"Are you all watching?"
はっ、はずか...あの、緊張しすぎて吐きそうなんだわ
"I'm so emba... um, I'm so nervous I feel like I'm gonna throw up."
今日はね、どうもみんなよろしくね！
"Well, everyone, thanks for being here today!"
えー、今日は、私の3Dお披露目見に来てくれてみんなありがとう！
"Um, thank you all so much for coming to see my 3D debut today!"
えー、今日は、えっと、Twitter、え、右上に、どっちだ？あ、こっち？こっちか？右上に書かれている、この不知火フレア3Dでたくさんツイートしてね！
"Um, today, on Twitter, um, on the top right—which way? Oh, this way? That way? On the top right, it says 'Shiranui Flare 3D', please tweet lots with that!"
そして、1位を目指すぞ！トレンド1位を目指そう！よろしくね、みんな！
"And let's aim for #1! Let's aim for #1 on the trends! Thanks everyone!"
そう、緊張しすぎて何がなんだかなんだわ。ありがとう、みんな！
"I'm so nervous I don't even know what's going on. Thank you, everyone!"
今日コメントもどんな感じよ？
"How are the comments looking?"
もう泣きそう。泣いてもいいよ。
"I'm about to cry. It's okay to cry."
泣けよ！言ったら泣けよ！私の代わりに泣いてくれ、頼むよ！
"Cry! If I say so, cry! Cry in my place, please!"
今日は、もうずっと緊張しすぎてて、なんだろう、もう吐きそうってずっと言ってて。
"Seriously today, I've been so nervous the whole time, like, I kept saying I felt like I was gonna throw up."
吐かないように今日は頑張るから、みんなも楽しんでくれたら嬉しいなって思います。
"I'll do my best not to throw up today, so I hope you all have fun too."
よく考えたらね、土足だね、私これ。ちょっと、みんな内緒ってことにして...
"Now that I think about it, I'm wearing shoes indoors here. Um, let's keep that between us..."
じゃあ、今日、これからたくさんやることがあるので、一旦外に移動しようかなって思います。お外でようね、みんな！
"Well then, today, there's a lot we're going to do from now on, so I think I'll move outside for a bit. Let's head outside, everyone!"
じゃあ、えー、外出？外出？
"So, um, going outside? Going outside?"
ジャンプしたほうがいいか？
"Should I jump?"
ジャンプ！移動しろよ！
"Jump! Move around!"
スタッフー！
"Staff!"
おい！スタッフー！頼むよー！
"Hey! Staff! Do something!"
画面映ってなーいって！
"The screen isn't showing anything!"
もう1回行きます。じゃあ行けよ！どい！
"Let's go again. Alright, here we go! Yah!"
じゃあ行けよ！あ、きもい！
"Here we go! Ah, gross!"
うわ、きもい！え、これきもいわ！ありがとう！
"Ew, gross! Wow, this is creepy! Thank you!"
これあのスパチャギミツク、あのスパチャ送ってくれたみんななのね？スパチャが、あの、気持ち悪いくらい…
"These are everyone who sent Superchats, right? The Superchats are, um, freakishly..."
キズナがよく飛んでおります。本当にありがとうみんな！
"Kizuna is flying around so much. Thank you all so much!"
いい感じに気持ち悪い感じになってます。なんかさ、上から降ってきてるのに、なんか下から飛んできてるように見えるのは気のせいか？
"It has a nicely creepy vibe. Wait, why does it look like they're flying up from below when they're falling from above? Is it just my imagination?"
え、ちょ、これ見て？なんかさ、下から上に上がってって…でバグってない？これ大丈夫？
"Wait, look at this! They're going from bottom to top... Wait, isn't it bugged? Is this okay?"
これ絶対なんかジャンプしてるみたいになってるやん、まあいいけどさ。
"It definitely looks like they're jumping, well, that's fine though."
そうね、えっと、この、この感じで、え、これどうしたらいいの？スパチャ。スパチャありがとう。え、これ一応片したほうがいいのかな？
"Right, um, with this, wait, what should I do with this? Superchats. Thanks for the Superchats. Um, should I clear these away?"
じゃあちょっと、あの、今日の主役は私なんだからね、ちょっと邪魔だから消してもらおうかな。消してもろって。
"Well, since I'm the main star today, I might have them disappear because they're in the way. Make them disappear."
いいか？ちょ、消えろ！消えろ！お、消えろ！
"Alright? Hey, vanish! Disappear! Oh, vanish!"
あ、じゃあね、まあ、すっきりしましたのでね、そろそろ誰かの声が聞こえるんじゃないかなと思うんですけど…けど…
"Ah, well, now that it's cleared up, I suppose we'll start hearing someone's voice soon... wait..."
遅いよ！
"You're late!"
待たせたな！おめでとうぺこーら！
"Kept you waiting! Congratulations Pekora!"
ありがとう！
"Thank you!"
おめでとうだな！
"Congratulations!"
いや、めっちゃめちゃんこ可愛いじゃん！え、スタイル良すぎてこれちょっと…
"Man, you're super, super cute! Wait, your figure is so good, like..."
足消えろなんぼ？
"How much to make your legs disappear?"
あ、ほら見るの？見せてごらん？見せてごらん？あ、ほら見るのよ？可愛い！
"Ah, look? Show me! Show me! Ah, look at this! Cute!"
あ、撮りたい！これはもうね、ちょっと早くいろんなところを回り込んで撮りたいですけど。
"Ah, I want to take pictures! I want to quickly run around and take pictures from all angles."
そうペコだよねえ！
"That's right, Peko!"
じゃあね、撮影会をしてもらおうかなと…
"So, um, I was thinking we could have a photo session..."
あ、いいか？じゃあね、ちょっとカメラから近い、船長から行かせていただいて。
"Ah, is that okay? Then let's start with the Captain, since she's closest to the camera."
うん、いいかな？おいしょ！
"Yeah, is that good? Heave-ho!"
ちょっとカメラの準備をしてもらって。
"Let's get the camera ready."
え、マジスタイルいいぺこだな、ちょっと。ねえ、並べてよ！並べてよ、ぺこ！
"Man, your figure is really good, Peko. Hey, line up with me! Line up, Peko!"
うんで真下から、これ下からこう写すとか！
"And right from below, like shooting from underneath!"
あ、カメラこっちか？あ、ジャンプで。
"Ah, is the camera this way? Ah, with a jump."
じゃあ、ちょっとカメラを切り替えるよ。ジャンプい！
"Alright, I'll switch cameras. Jum-py!"
ナイスぺこ！ここめっちゃ寒そうぺこ、ここ！
"Nice Peko! This place looks super cold, Peko!"
寒しかよ、ちょっと。もう一回、もう一回頼むで。ジャンプ！
"It's freezing, man. Do it again, do it again please. Jump!"
なんでだよ！
"Why?!"
あ、ここね？ここね？
"Ah, here? Here?"
クリストファー
"Christopher"
あ、ここはエルフの森ぺこか？これまさんの？
"Ah, is this the Elven forest, Peko? Is this Ma-san's?"
いや、秋なんだよな、これもうな。秋だね。あははは。
"Nah, it's autumn already, you know. It's autumn. Ahahaha."
しずかか、しずかな…
"Quiet, quiet..."
しずかな秋の森ぺこだね。
"It's a quiet autumn forest, Peko."
ちょっと、あの草木もね、ボウボウしてるけど、これでね、カメラ撮ってもらうかと思いつつ。
"Um, the plants and trees are overgrown, but I thought about having them take a picture with this."
はい、これか？写り、写るか？ちょっと今日、う、う、スタッフー
"Yes, this? Will it show? Will it capture? Today, um, um, staffー"
あ、踏んだ！あ、来て来て来て！やばい！曲がった！
"Ah, you stepped on it! Ah, come come come! Oh no! It bent!"
こちらご覧ください。はい、ぺこらちゃんの、えっと、どう写すのが…隠すな、隠すな！
"Please look at this. Yes, Pekora-chan's, um, how should I shoot it... Don't hide it, don't hide it!"
こう、なんやろね。あの、腰の、ね？腰の、なんだ、あの、穴って言ったらなんか…こら！
"Like, how should I put it. Um, the waist, you know? The waist, what is it, if I call it a hole..."
エロいじゃん。ちょっと待って。こら！こら！
"That's lewd. Hold on. Hey! Hey!"
はい、笑って笑って。はい、船長今撮影中ですよ。
"Yes, smile, smile. Yes, the Captain is shooting right now."
普段は、はじめて見るのかな？え、可愛い！
"Is this the first time seeing it normally? Eh, cute!"
可愛い！え、マジで可愛い！
"Cute! Wow, seriously cute!"
見えてるのかな？
"Can they see it?"
あ、振り返え、あの、歩いてってさ、振り返ってこっちぐるって…
"Ah, turn back, um, walk away, turn around and spin this way..."
こういうこと？え、可愛いじゃん！
"Like this? Eh, that's cute!"
限界、満身創痍じゃん、今。満身創痍になってるぺこ。
"You're at your limit, battered and bruised right now. You're battered, Peko."
ほら、じゃあちょっと、あのさ、いいかな？ちょっと、うん、なに？踏んで、踏んでもらっても…
"Look, so um, is it okay? Just, um, what? Even if you step, step on me..."
バカかよ！お願い、お願い、お願い、ちょっと踏んで…
"Are you an idiot?! Please, please, please, step on me a bit..."
うわ！やばい！やばいぺこ！なんだこれ！
"Whoa! Oh no! This is bad, Peko! What is this?!"
楽しそう！マジで苦しいよ！フレア、フレア、キック、キック、キック！
"Looks fun! It's seriously painful! Flare, Flare, kick, kick, kick!"
キック！こう…え、かっこいい！
"Kick! Like this... Whoa, cool!"
かっこいい！交代する？交代する？
"Cool! Switch places? Switch places?"
嫁行ってこい！嫁行ってくる！ノエル？ノエル？
"Go get married! I'm going to get married! Noel? Noel?"
じゃあちょっと、切な繋がりでだんちょ…あ、はい。
"Well then, in a bittersweet connection, Danchou... Ah, yes."
あ、フレア！
"Ah, Flare!"
ノエル、私泣いてる！ノエル出てきて！ノエル出てきて、ぺこ！
"Noel, I'm crying! Noel come out! Noel come out, Peko!"
ノエル、お前泣いてるのか？いや、泣いてないよ！全然泣いてないよ！
"Noel, are you crying? Nah, I'm not crying at all!"
ノエル顔赤いよ！
"Noel, your face is red!"
赤いよ！ぺこちゃんだもん！
"It is red! Because it's Pekora-chan!"
え、あの、そう、やって欲しかったことがあって、だんちょ…
"Um, so, there was something I wanted you to do, Danchou..."
ちょっと自分の背中見せびらかすのやめて。
Stop showing off your back like that!
だってさ、ここにいるからさ。
Because I'm right here, you know.
なんでだ？
Why's that?
やばい、ノエルが横になり始めたぺこ、危ない。
Oh no, Noel's starting to lie down, watch out!
こういうことね、こう、こういうことでいいのか。
Ah, like this? Is this what you mean?
これ、草のせいで。
Because of the grass,
ノエルが見えない。
I can't see Noel.
ノエルがやばい、草が邪魔すぎる。
Noel, oh no, the grass is way too in the way!
どこ？ノエル、立ってる？
Where are you? Noel, are you standing?
ノエル、立ってるか？大丈夫か？
Noel, are you standing? Are you okay?
腰が抜けてる？嘘でしょ？
Your legs are giving out? No way!
でも腰が抜けてる、大丈夫？
But your legs are giving out, are you okay?
立てる？立てる。
Can you stand? I can stand.
船長、でも逆に団長フレアを、うん、うん、見たいよ上から。
Senchou, but I actually wanna see Captain Flare from above—
あ、逆に下から押してほしいのね？腰押してあげる。
Ah, you want me to push from below? I'll push your hips.
めりめり、横になっちゃって、腰寝ればいいの？
Sinking in, lying sideways, should I just lie my hips down?
うん。
Yeah.
これなんてもう三期生のさ、高齢ぺこだ、高齢のやつじゃんね。
This is like, you know, the 3rd gen tradition, right?
ねぇ！草が邪魔すぎ！誰だよこのセレクトしたやつ！
Hey! The grass is way too annoying! Who selected this?!
ノエルが切れてる、切れてる、切れてるみたいな。
Noel's cut off, cut off, cut off like that.
草！これ、雪のせいのほうがよかったのかな？草邪魔だな！
Was snow better than this? The grass is so annoying!
草邪魔じゃない？
Isn't the grass annoying?
いや、かわいいな。ぺこちゃん、じゃあ、行く？
Man, so cute. Peko-chan, shall we go?
うん、ほい。
Yeah, oop.
草邪魔だね、エルフの森も燃やそう。
The grass is annoying, let's burn down the elf forest too.
ね、燃やそう、燃やそう、燃やすしかないわ。
Yeah, let's burn it, we have no choice.
温便に解決する方法はないのか？
Isn't there a way to solve this peacefully?
船長はやっぱり四つんばいになって。
Senchou should definitely get on all fours.
なん で ？
Why?!
えへへ、だって女の子みんな四つんばいになるべきだ。もっとせつ、
Because all girls should get on all fours. More sezu—
なに言ってんだぺこら。きゅってね。
What are you saying, Pekora? Squish like that.
あ、いいね、いいね。きゅってやって、こっち向いて、はい、みゃんこのポーズで、みゃん。
Do a squish, face this way, yes, cat pose, meow.
あー、かわいい！
Aah, so cute!
これ全員いのかな？この、のりきじゃなさそうなみゃんこ、いいね。
Is everyone here? This unenthusiastic cat, I like it.
え、待って、船ちゃん、そう、ききたくなることぺこだけど、船ちゃんさ、なんかさ、好きなところないの？
Wait, Furea-chan, I'm curious about this, but don't you have a favorite spot?
この、ここを見てほしいっていうさ、自分の「お気に入り」っぽい、お気に入りっぽいところってあるぺこ？
Like a spot where you want us to look, your favorite spot?
弓見ながら見に来てくれたらいいよ。
You can come check it out while looking at the bow.
え！まじ？しつれー。
Eh! Really? Rude.
あ、私の良さはみんなが切り抜いてくれるから。
Ah, my greatness will be clipped out by everyone, so.
ああ、そうよね。でも船長はやっぱ足と、あのやっぱ腰のところの穴がね、やっぱりお気に入りポイントかな？
Your legs and the hole around your waist are your favorite points?
確かに、ふくらはぎがすごいむちっとしてって。
That's true, your calves are super plump.
めっちゃ、あー、きれいだねー。
Super, ah, so pretty.
やば、れあ、美しいよ！
Man, Rea, you're gorgeous!
草刈りって、マジで！
Grass cutting, seriously!
邪魔くせえんだよ！
It's so annoying!
れーちゃんは、れーちゃんないの？
Rei-chan, don't you have one?
え、じゃ、れーちゃん撮る？撮る？れーちゃん撮ってって。
Then, should I take Rei-chan? Take a picture of Rei-chan.
いいよ。え、フレアさ、いつものさ、あのさ、なんかこうやってかっこよくしてるポーズほしい。
Sure. Flare, I want that usual pose of yours where you look cool.
こうやって、こうやってこうやってさ、どうやって？そうやってやって、こう。あ、そうそうそうそう。
Like this, like this, like this, how? Do it like that, like this. Ah, yeah.
え、いつものかっこいいちょっと、なでぼしというか、かっこよく決めてほしい。こういうやつ。で、あの、うさぎ跳びしてほしい。
Your usual cool pose, petting the star, make it look cool. And do rabbit jumps.
え、どういうこと？このままうさぎ跳び？
Eh, what do you mean? Rabbit jumps just like this?
このまま、いっぱいいろんな仕草がほしいから、うさぎ跳びしてほしい。
I want all kinds of poses, so do rabbit jumps.
もうね、武者震いもね、いま言いたかったね、興奮してるからね。分かるよ。
I wanted to say I'm trembling with excitement, I get it.
興奮してんだ、興奮。じゃあ、うさぎのスタイルいいから。
You're excited. Well, the rabbit style is good, so.
そう、あと何だろ？え、じゃあカメラ覗き込んで、フレア。
Yeah, what else? Then peer into the camera, Flare.
あ、いいね、いいね。覗き込んで、覗き込んで。うん。
Ah, nice, nice. Peer in, peer in. Yeah.
あ、かわいい！あ、かわいい！ウィンクしとこ。
Ah, so cute! Ah, so cute! Wink.
でも切り抜きポイントだぞ。きゅるきゅるいて、ハッシュタグでつぶやいて。
But this is a clipping point. Make it cute, tweet with the hashtag.
いいぞ、つぶやけ。
Good, tweet it.
いいぞー！いいねー！
Nice! Awesome!
ちょっと待って。え、スタイル足とかきれいだね。
Wait a minute. Eh, your legs and style are so pretty.
ね、あ、あれとかしたくない？お辞儀とかさ、ほら。配信の時してた？お辞儀。
Don't you want to do a bow? Look. Did you bow during streams?
お辞儀決めて。
Strike a bow.
今日はみんな来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you everyone for coming today!
あ、ちょっと！ここいい！
Ah, wait! Right here is good!
いい！いい感じだよ。
Good! It's a good vibe.
え、いいのか？今日ま、今日までよ、本当に。
Eh, is that okay? Today, just until today, seriously.
いやー、素敵だなー。
Man, it's wonderful.
え、ノエルはへきほかりなんか持って、腰のことある場合じゃねえぞ。
Noel's holding a wall, this isn't the time to worry about her waist.
え、ぐるって回ってほしい、なんか。
Eh, I want you to spin around.
いいね、いいね。ぐるっていうのは、その本当ぐるっとターンみたいな。
Nice, nice. When I say spin, it's like a full turn.
そっか、ターン！ターン！
I see, a turn! Turn!
あ、髪の毛が、髪の毛が。
Ah, your hair, your hair.
髪の毛、ロングだから。
Your hair is long, so.
うん、きれいだね、やっぱ。髪が。
Yeah, it's pretty. Your hair.
え、ここを映されてる、どこを映してるのってなるわ。
People will wonder where this is being filmed and what's shown.
脇、脇見て！手上げて貰って。
Look at the armpits! Raise your hands.
手上げて貰って、ちょっとだけよ。
Raise your hands, just a little bit.
すごい！えこちゃん、下から。
Amazing! Peko-chan, from below.
せっかくは、せっかく変態の換気が、すごい。恥ずかしがる。
Since it's a pervert's ventilation, it's amazing. Getting all embarrassed.
かわいい！かわいい！
Cute! Cute!
恥ずかしいから、もう終わり？もう終わり？
It's embarrassing, is it over already?
もう終わり？うん、もう終わり。
Already over? Yeah, already over.
いや、みんな、いっぱい写真撮れました？スクショ撮ってくれました？
Did everyone take lots of pictures? Did you take screenshots?
撮ってくれた？え？
Did you take them? Eh?
もういい？まあね、確かに我々ばっか撮っててもね、実はまだ後ろに控えている人。
True, if we're just taking pictures of ourselves, people are waiting in the back.
まだいますからね。あ、その、その背中を撮るぞ。
They're still here, you know. Ah, take pictures of that back.
その背中がね、いいんだよね。
That back is really nice, you know.
その背中やっぱいいペコだよね。
That back is a really good Peko.
やっぱ、ロングが。
Long hair is just...
草が邪魔だな 草が邪魔だな ほんとに草が邪魔だな
The grass is in the way... The grass is so in the way!
でもね 草が多いんだな
There really is a lot of grass.
まあきれいな
Well, it's pretty.
いやね、ちょっと やっぱり草邪魔だな。
But you know... the grass is still in the way.
え、なんかさ、ノエルのさ、メイス貸してよ。
Hey, can I borrow Noel's mace?
あ、メイス出す？
Oh, you want to bring out the mace?
うん、うん、出る？メイス、メイス。
Yeah, yeah, will it come out? Mace, mace.
出るかな？出るかな？
Will it come out? Will it?
いでよ！出る？メイス。
Come forth! Will it appear, mace?
じゃ、ちょっとフレアかっこよく出す。
Okay, Flare is gonna look cool bringing it out.
メイス持たせて？出す時のやつやって。
Give me the mace? Do the summoning pose.
出す時のやつ（笑）
The summoning pose! (Laughs)
エイショ、エイショ、エイショ。エイショ？メイス出す？エイショ。
Heave-ho, heave-ho! Heave-ho? Bring out the mace? Heave-ho!
三番だー。
Number three!
そういう感じ？毎回それ出してないよ、団長。
Is that how it is? You don't always do that, Danchou.
あ、あ、あ、あ きたきたきたきた、きてるね。
Ah, ah, ah, ah! It's coming, it's coming!
ちょっと、ちょっと怪しいけど。
It's looking a little... a little suspicious, though.
カッコつけね。ちょっと怪しいけど。
Trying to look cool, but kinda suspicious.
団長刺しちゃった。ちょっと、あ、間違えちゃった。
I stabbed Danchou! Wait, oops, I messed up.
普通に真似しちゃってる。
I'm just copying her normally.
すごい人形みたいに乗っとる。
It's perched on me like a doll.
これが赤狼ですか？
Is this the Sekirou?
あ、なるほど。じゃあ ええ、こういう
Ah, I see. So... like this,
あ、でも、あっ、逆向いとるわ、これ。向いてねえ！
Oh wait, it's facing backward! It's not facing right!
こういう、こういう。メイスがね、どこ、どこ？
Like this, like this. Where's the mace, where?
メイスがどこ、どこ？あ、だから変な位置に、変な位置に...
Where's the mace? Ah, so it's in a weird spot...
メイスがどうしようもねえわ、これ。
There's just no helping this mace placement!
あのね、これ団長の意思を継いどるからテレちゃってんだよ、メイス。
You know, since it inherits Danchou's will, it's acting all shy!
なんか、ノエルちょっと、フレアの3Dで興奮しとる。
Noel seems a bit excited over Flare's 3D stream.
いや、ほんとはこうね、ダークソウルみたいにね、こういうのやりたかったんだけど。
I mean, I really wanted to do something like Dark Souls with this...
こう、こうやってしまうから。
But it ends up looking like this!
いや、でも、こうね、ダークソウルみたいにね、こういうのやりたかったんだけど、どう考えても位置がおかしいで。
I wanted to do something like Dark Souls, but no matter how you look at it, the position is wrong!
あ、でも、いい感じ、いい感じ。あ、いいめいめいめい、あ、こう。
Ah, but it's looking good, looking good. Ah, wait, like this.
持ってる。逆か？逆か？
I'm holding it. Is it backward? Is it?
団長のメイスをフレアが持ってる。
Flare is holding Danchou's mace!
めっちゃ、こう、そんな急にこう動かさないで。
Hey, don't move it around so suddenly!
触れすぎ。いいえ、でかくなった、なんか。
Touching too much. Wait, it got bigger, somehow?
ちょっと興奮してちょっとでかくなって。
It got excited and grew a bit larger.
そうやね、ボルトのメイスになった。あ、突っ立った。
Yeah, it became Bolte's mace. Oh, it poked out.
あ、かっこいいかっこいい。あ、いいね、かっこいいよ。
Ah, cool, cool. Ah, nice, it's cool!
スイカ割してるみたいでいいね。そう、そう。
It's nice, looks like watermelon splitting. Yeah, exactly.
呑気だね。あ、だから、あ、この、このカメラにね、向かって、バーン、かっこいい、ペコ、いける。
So laid-back. Ah, so facing this camera, bam, cool, Pekora, you can do it!
レッシャどうだ？満足したか、レッシャ？いいか？
How's Ressha? Are you satisfied, Ressha? Is it good?
いやもう、大満足だよ。なんか、もうボケーと見ちゃった、ずっと見てるわ。
I'm super satisfied! I just stared at it blankly, keep watching.
認め、認めとる。やばいもうこれ。
She admits it. This is dangerous now.
いややっぱりさ、ぺこらちゃんってかっこいいところもあるぺこだけど、やっぱかわいいとこもあるぺこじゃん。
But you know, Pekora-chan has cool sides, but she also has cute sides, right?
アイドルポーズをお願いしてもいいぺこですか？
May I ask for an idol pose?
どういう？どういうポーズ？ぺこらが思うアイドルのポーズをお願いするぺこだよ。
What kind? What kind of pose? An idol pose that Pekora imagines, please!
最後に決めたってくだせえ。あ、テレてんね、テレてんね。
Give us a final pose! Ah, she's getting shy, getting shy.
ぺこらも、ぺこらも、もう、恥ずかしがってるぺこじゃん。
Pekora's acting all embarrassed too!
やってごらん。ダッチュウのとか？ねえ？
Go on, try it. Danchou's style? Right?
マリに影響されてる。
She's being influenced by Marine.
いや、フレアそれはちょっと。どういうポーズ？あ、いいじゃん、ダッチュウのいいじゃん。やって、ダッチュウのって言うんだよ。分かった？ダッチュウの……
Flare, that's a bit... What kind of pose? Ah, that's good, Danchou's is good. Do it, say "Danchou's". Understood? Danchou's...
でん！かわいい！ハジライが大事なんだなと思った。
Ta-da! So cute! I realized that bashfulness is important.
見習わね、見習わね。見習わね。
I gotta learn from this, gotta learn.
いや、かわいいな。ねえ、こうだ。
Man, she's so cute. Right, like this.
これや。いいのか？これでいいのか？いいよ。
This is it. Is this good? Is this okay? Good.
いいよ、可愛いよ。もうたまらん、もうこの揺れるポニーテールがね。
Good, cute. I can't take it, this swaying ponytail is...
そう、そう。ポイントだね。あ、見てみて、綺麗だよ。
Yeah, yeah. That's the point. Ah, look, look, it's pretty.
あ、もう、あ、すぐ時間みたいだ。時間だ。
Ah, wait, looks like time's up. It's time.
あ、ぺこらちゃんもフレア、限界になっためっちゃ。
Ah, Pekora-chan and Flare reached their limit!
頑張ってぺこだよ。
Do your best, Peko!
そうだよ、うれら頑張れ。ありがとね。見てからね。頑張れよ。ありがと。
That's right, Urera, do your best. Thanks! Watch from now on. Do your best. Thanks.
じゃあね、みんなもずっといてくれてるかなって、切り抜き頼むぜ。
Well, I'm counting on you guys to clip this stream!
じゃあね、1回、あの、場所移動しようかなと思うよ。またジャンプするから頼むよ。上、頼むぜ、マジ。いくよ。はい。
Now, I think we'll move locations once. I'm gonna jump again, so please! Up, seriously, please. Here we go. Yes.
うえ、おまえ、やったな。もっかい行きます。はい。
Whoa, hey, you did it! Let's go again. Yes!
このタイミングだった。いや、やっぱ秋なんだよな。
At this timing? Well, it is autumn after all.
今日は秋ってこと いいんじゃないでしょうか。
Today is autumn, wouldn't you say?
なあ、次のコーナーに 行ってみましょう。来るかな？
Well, let's move on to the next corner. Will it come?
来るか？ おお おお おお おお おお
Will it come? Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh!
にゃお、お、にゃ、にゃお、にゃお、あ、にゃお、すごい。
Nyao, oh, nyao, nyao, nyao, oh, nyao, amazing!
すごい、可愛いこの黒猫で。
Amazing, this black cat is so cute.
ここ可愛い、この猫顔でね。猫顔って。可愛い、可愛い、超強い。
So cute, this cat face. Cat face! Cute, cute, super strong.
うーにゃー。異色のコンビだね。
U-nya! What an unusual combination.
なんか異色のコンビが、いいね。うーにゃー、うーにゃー。ありがとう。
An unusual duo, how nice. U-nya, u-nya. Thank you!
うーにゃー。
U-nya!
メイプル、ありがとう！
Maple, thank you!
めちゃくちゃ可愛いよ。
It's super cute.
ほんと可愛いよ。
Truly cute.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
入ってないよ、それは。
That's not included.
どうしよう？
What should I do?
今日はね、私を盛り上げるために
Today, to hype me up,
ふぶき先輩とみこ先輩も呼んじゃいました。
I invited Fubuki-senpai and Miko-senpai too.
いやいけぼ、ありがとうございます。
Yeah, handsome voice, thank you very much.
いやぁ、いいよね。
Yeah, it's nice, right?
あの、みこ先輩とふぶき先輩ってな、なんだって？
Um, Miko-senpai and Fubuki-senpai... what was it?
いいの、こんなね、シチュ...って、だって、みこちゃん、いいのかな、我々そんなの。
Is it okay for us to have such a... wait, Miko-chan, is it okay for us to do that?
すごい、お前ら、え、どっちだ？
Amazing, you guys, eh, which is it?
どっちなんだきてもいいのかな、いいのかな。
Whichever one, is it okay to come?
うん、これ説明してくれるって。
Um, she said she'll explain it.
今日は、二人にプロデューサーになってもらって、
Today, I'll have the two of you become producers,
私が、あの、先輩同士のね、ま、今日だけ先輩っていう扱いをするから
and since I'm treating you as my senpais just for today...
先輩たちの望むシチュエーションを、まあ、ちょっとやってみようかなって、思います！
...I thought we could try acting out the situations that you senpais desire!
お前、そんなこと言ったらお前のその首元とか腰についてるボタンのことタピオカって言うぞ。
If you say stuff like that, I'm gonna call those buttons on your neck and waist tapioca!
キャッチーとそれをパッとやってるからやめてもらってもいいですか？これからコラボ。
Can you stop using 'catchy' like that so suddenly? We're collaborating right now.
それはだんだんそれにみえてくるでしょ、ふぶちゃん。やめてくださいよ。
You'll gradually start seeing it as that, Fubuki-chan. Please stop.
タピオカだ、タピオカよって言ってポチって取る。
It's tapioca, it's tapioca, and pop you take it.
美味しいね！
Delicious, right?
やばいよ、ふぶちゃんがずっとデレデレだよ、たぶん。
It's dangerous, Fubuki-chan is probably being all mushy the whole time.
いや、すごい顔してるね。
Man, what a face she's making.
やばいよ、今本当にニタニタしながら顔してるね。
It's dangerous, right now she's really grinning and making that face.
正面に出たら多分もう顔にモザイクがかかってる顔してるから今ダメなんだね。
If she goes to the front, her face probably has a mosaic on it right now, so it's no good.
映し出されません、ちょっと。
It won't show on screen, wait a sec.
いや、これいいの？みこたちが、なんでも、なんでも聞いてくれるって、タピオカ、タピオカって。
Wait, is this okay? Miko and them will listen to anything, saying 'tapioca, tapioca'.
タピオカにすんじゃねえよ！
Don't turn it into tapioca!
救えよ！
Save me!
助かる。タピオカ助かる。タピオカにしか見えなくなっちゃったね。
Saved. Tapioca is a lifesaver. It's starting to look only like tapioca.
やめろ、おかしくなっちゃったね。ってことでシチュエーションボイスということでね、うん。
Stop it, you've gone crazy. So, for the situation voice, yeah.
やらせるか、じゃあ！
You're gonna make us do it, huh!
はい。いいんですか？やっちゃってもいいんですか？
Yes. Is it okay? Is it okay if I do it?
え、みこちゃん、なんか、なんか楽しそうだなこの二人。やらせたいこと
Eh, Miko-chan, somehow, these two look like they're having fun. The things they want us to do,
いいの？え、みこの席でいいんですか？いいよ、どうぞどうぞ！
is it okay? Eh, is it okay in Miko's seat? Sure, go ahead!
え、じゃあね、え、これカメラって寄ってもらえるんですか？ちょっと。
Eh, then, eh, can the camera zoom in on us a bit?
やれ、そうだそうだ。もっとフレアちゃんの顔に寄りで、寄りでやってもらって。
Do it, that's right. Zoom in closer on Flare-chan's face and do it.
あの、やってほしいシチュエーションがみこはありまして、あの、壁ドン、壁ドンをする
Um, Miko has a situation she wants: doing a kabedon, doing a kabedon...
壁ドンをして、そっから、あの、やっぱフレアちゃんってね、テレ屋さんなんですよ、この子。壁、待って、壁...
...doing a kabedon, and from there, well, Flare-chan is a shy person, you see. Kabedon, wait, kabe...
え、壁され...待って、フレアちゃん、あ、待って、今さ...
Eh, getting kabe... wait, Flare-chan, ah, wait, right now...
みんな見てるリスナーがさ、フレアちゃんのさ、その右とか左だから手バーンってさ、モニターにギャンってやったら自分が壁ドンしてる側になれるのでは！
...everyone watching, the listeners, if you just slap your hand right or left onto the monitor like bam, you can be on the side doing the kabedon!
めっちゃ天才じゃないですか、みこちゃん！天才だ！
Aren't you a total genius, Miko-chan! A genius!
でき...今すぐ画面をフルスクリーンにしてだな、いいのフルスクリーン
Can you... make the screen full-screen right now, okay, full-screen...
高画質で見せて、見てもらって、テレビとかで見てもらってね。見てもら、4Kで見てもらって。
...show it in high quality, have them look at it on a TV or something. Have them look at it in 4K.
うんうんうん。これ、なんかできそうな、オッケー出ましたよ、これ。オッケー出ましたね。
Yeah yeah yeah. This, looks doable, okay, permission granted. Permission granted.
じゃあ、ちょっと、あの、私たち壁ドンをするので、フレアちゃんはそれで結構、あの、照れて、あの、一言二言いただけたらなと、思います。
Well then, since we'll be doing a kabedon, I hope Flare-chan can get quite shy about it and say a word or two.
はい。よろしいでしょうか？
Right. Is that alright?
わか、わかった。
Un- understood.
楽しみだな。楽しみだな。
I'm looking forward to it. I'm looking forward to it.
じゃあ、ドーンと仕やってくださいよ。
Then, please go ahead and do it with a bang.
はい。それでは、フレアちゃんの我々が壁ドンしたら、フレアちゃんを触るまで、3、2、1、ドン！
Right. Then, 3, 2, 1, boom! Until we touch Flare-chan after doing a kabedon!
急に壁ドンとかされると、ちょっとテレるんだけど。え、何？
When you suddenly do a kabedon or something, I get a little shy. Eh, what?
フレアちゃん、言いたいことあるならハッキリ言いよ。
Flare-chan, if you have something to say, say it clearly.
超可愛い！今、なんだ、今の手にス、ズンって、ズンってやったのがめっちゃ可愛いの。
Super cute! Right now, what was that, doing a thud, thud with your hands was super cute.
その、ズンってやった手をお前がガッて掴みたかった。なんだよ！
I wanted to grab that hand that went thud. What the heck!
え、ちょ、今さ、結構みこちゃん想像以上にさ、破壊力があってちょっと...
Eh, wait, right now, Miko-chan's destructive power was way beyond imagination, so...
なんか、泣きたくなっちゃった！
...somehow, I felt like crying!
なんで！この、この子と付き合えるって...この子！これ付き合ってるみたいな！
Why! Being able to go out with this kid... this kid! It's like going out!
やばいね、これは。いや、嫁の後ろにいるからさ。そう。
This is dangerous. Well, because my wife is behind me. Yeah.
怖い。こわ、後ろで嫁が見ている。
Scary. Sca-, my wife is watching from behind.
やばいやばいやばい。
Dangerous dangerous dangerous.
え、じゃあ、ふぶちゃんは、ふぶちゃん。え、どうしよう。え、なんだろう、可愛い方を見たからどうなんだろう、みんなカッコいい方を見たいのかな？
Eh, then, Fubuki-chan, Fubuki-chan. Eh, what should I do. Eh, I wonder, since you saw the cute side, I wonder what's up, does everyone want to see the cool side?
どうだろう。カッコいいのも、見たいのかな？
I wonder. Do you want to see the cool side too?
今日、私のお披露目だというのに！
Even though today is my reveal!
あ、いいよ
Ah, sure.
ほら、ボイス欲しいのかな、みんなどうなんだろ？
Hey, I wonder if everyone wants voice packs.
可愛いものが見たい？みんな。
Do you want to see something cute, everyone?
ちょっとコメントを見てみよう。
Let's check the comments.
「見たい」「見たいぞ」って言ってるよ。
They're saying "I want to see it" and "Show me."
あ、本当に？ 欲しがりさんね。
Oh really? You greedy guys.
ああ、ほらくんもみたいじゃ、逆に壁ドンする？
Ah, do you want to see Hora-kun too? Or kabedon?
壁ドンする？ 逆にね、逆壁ドンになるってことね、うん。
Kabedon? Conversely, making it a reverse kabedon, right? Yeah.
あ、それか、あ、もっといいこと思いついた。
Ah, or rather, I just thought of an even better idea.
今日ってさ、土曜日じゃん。
Today is Saturday, right?
みんなさ、お仕事でやっぱ疲れてるじゃん。
Everyone's tired from work, right?
撫でてもらってさ、頭なでなでしてもらおうぜ。
So let's get petted, have our heads stroked!
で、あの、今週も、頑張ってねみんな、えらいぞって。
And um, today and this week, you did your best, everyone, you're amazing!
マジで尻尾が死ぬほど暴れてますよ、このキツネちゃん。ちょっとお願いしていいですか？今週もあの、頑張んだよ、お。
Seriously, my tail is thrashing like crazy, this fox girl. Could I ask you? I worked hard this week too, oh.
わかりました、じゃあ、ほらで、褒めてもらえる？
Understood. Then, can I get praised by Hora?
いやいや、フレアで、フレアでお願いします。フレアで？フレアでお願いします。
No no, with Flare! Please do it with Flare! With Flare? Please do it with Flare!
サーバー、お姉さん出してもろて、うふふ、おお。
Server, get big sis to come out! Hehe, oh.
じゃあ、そんなフレアのお仕事がんばったみんなをよしよしってしてくれるシチュで、3、2、1、どうぞ。
Now, in a scenario where Flare praises everyone who worked hard with a "yoshi yoshi", 3, 2, 1, go!
おつかれさま、お仕事よく頑張ったね。
Good job. You worked really hard.
よしよし…にゃーん！
Yoshi yoshi... nyan!
なんかどんなのにぶつけてきたね、とんでもない、にゃーん！
What kind of thing did you hit me with? Unbelievable, nya~n.
甘やかしてると見せかけて、甘えてきているおるぞ、そういうことか。
Pretending to spoil you, but actually coming to get spoiled yourself, is that it?
いや可愛い、めっちょ可愛い。
No, cute, super cute!
ほんとにね、みこ感動しすぎちゃってほんとに、ほんとに感動しすぎても本当に、ああ、可愛いありがとう！
Seriously, Miko was so touched, really... Ah, cute, thank you!
はい、親犬系だよ。どうですか、これ？
Yes, parent-dog type. How's this?
なんかまだありますか？まだやっても、まだやっていいんですか？
Is there more? Can we still do more, is it okay?
ええ、じゃあさ、え、いいみこ、うん、いいよ。
Eh, then, good Miko... yeah, okay.
じゃあ、ちょっとフレアちゃんに、めっちら、あの、やっぱり顔顔寄りで、顔顔寄りで、あの、いつもありがとうねって言ってほしい。
Then, I want Flare-chan to be super close to my face, and say "Always thank you" to me.
オッケー。
Okay.
じゃあ、コメント寄ってもらって、
Then get close to Komesa,
あ、その後にさ、にゃって言ってほしい。
Ah, and after that, I want you to say "nya".
いや猫やんけ！いや、猫やんけしてくれよ、猫やんけ。
No, that's a cat! No, do the cat thing!
アップになったりも、後ろ来て、後ろ来て、後ろに来て。
Becoming a close-up, or coming behind, coming behind.
後ろに来て？
Come behind me?
そうそう、後ろ、後ろ向いて、後ろ向いて、で、振り返ってほしいな。そうそうそうそう、そう、721でフレアちゃって呼んでもらって、振り返ってセリフ言ってくれ。
Yeah. Turn around, and call out "Flare-chan", and turn around to say the line.
えっと、こうやってセリフなんだっけ？
Um, what was the line again?
いつもありがとう、にゃん。
Thank you as always, nyan.
よかった、振り返りフレム。
Good, looking back Furemu.
上手、すごいじゃん。
Great, amazing.
いいよ。
Good.
ふ、ふれあー！
Fure-a-!
いつもありがとう、にゃん。
Thank you as always, nyan.
なんだこれ？
What is this?
可愛い、可愛い、可愛い！
Cute, cute, cute!
いや、髪のなめきかたの振り返りからだといいかも、丁寧すぎるんだが、ほうほう。
Man, the way she licks her hair and the dialogue after turning around is way too polite.
いや、ポニーテールってやっぱいいよね、ええやろ。
Man, ponytails are the best, right? Yeah.
いっぱい見てるよ、もう、くまなく見てるよ、もう、Twitterにもいっぱい投稿してたかな。
Look a lot. I'm looking a lot. I posted a lot on Twitter too, right?
ありがとう。
Thank you.
クッションめちゃめちゃしてるからな。
Because I'm hugging the cushion so much.
じゃあ、なんか最後に、あれか。
Then, is it the last one?
ある、最後。
There is, the last.
ええー！
Ehh!
ちょっと、これちょっと、あれかな、だめかな、みんな死んじゃうかもしれないな。
Wait, is this... is it no good? Everyone might die from cuteness.
何ですか？
What is it?
あの、アップ、また顔アップになっちゃうんだけど、アップね。
Um, close-up, it's going to be a face close-up again, but close-up, yeah.
あの、ちゅ、ちゅ、ちゅ、ちゅ。
Um, wait wait wait wait...
なあ、限界と限界か！
Right? Is this the limit of limits?
いいぞ、いいぞ、ちゅ、好きだよみたいな。
Good, good, "chu", "I love you" sort of thing.
ほしいな、おじさんほしいな、ほしいな。
I want it, this old man wants it.
むきゅみこちゃん、フレアちゃんからの「ちゅ」欲しいな！
Mukyu Miko-chan, I want a "chu" from Furea-chan!
キス顔ってことですよね？そうそうそうそう。
You mean a kiss face? Exactly.
そうですね、ちゅってやって、好きだよ。
That's right. Do "chu", and "I love you".
お願いいたしまーす、お願いしまーす。
Please, I beg you.
じゃあ行きますよ、じゃあそんなフレアのちゅってやって好きだよまで、3、2、1、どうぞ。
Then, in a scenario from Flare doing "chu" and saying "I love you", 3, 2, 1, go!
おー、好きだよ、ちゅ。
Oh, I love you. Chu!
かわいすぎた、わ、ちょ、待って、そう来るとまずちょっとびっくりした。
Too cute! Wow, wait, when it came like that, I was a bit surprised.
ほんとにね、お姉さん的な感じに1人来るかと思いきや、とんでもねえ破壊力が来て来て。
I thought only one big sis type would come, but incredible destructive power came!
ちょっとおじさんここが持たないよー！
Wait, I can't take this anymore!
やばいで、限界限界
This is bad, I'm at my limit!
キツネになってるよ。
Kitsune-san has become an old man.
みこおじさんになっちゃうよ。
Miko-san has become an old man.
もう死んだ、もうこれ今...
I'm already dead... This is...
恥ずかしいね。
It's embarrassing, right?
6万人が見てたぞ、まえ...
60,000 people were watching, you know!
何人？！
How many?!
何人見られてた...
How many people were watching?!
何人生き返らせてると思ってんだ、みんな。
Everyone thought they were being revived!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
死んで今一瞬でで再生してるぞ！
They're being revived in a split second!
何度でも...おれたちゃ満足でよ。
Even if it's 10,000 times, we're satisfied!
ありがとお腹いっぱいだよ。
Thank you, I'm stuffed!
かわいい。
Cute!
レジェンダリー！かわいい。
Legendary! Cute!
また、3Dでもコラボしようね。
Let's collaborate with us 3D too, right?
しましょうね！
Let's do that!
うんうんうんうん、しようね！
Yeah, let's do it!
しよう、みこ先輩もね、コラボしようね！
Miko-senpai, let's collaborate too, right?
約束したからね、逃がさないぞ。
It's a promise, so don't back out!
おめでとう！ふねや。
Congratulations!
おめでとう、ふぶき。
Congratulations, Fubuki!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
おめでとう！ありがとう！かわいい！
Congratulations! Thank you! Cute!
この後もね、がんばってね！はい！がんばって！
Work hard after this too! Okay! Good luck!
ずっとお空から見てるよ。
I've been watching from the sky all along.
死ぬのか？
Are you dying?
ありがとう、ふねや。
Thank you, Fubuki.
最後にさ、最後にさ、またもう一回。なぜなんですか？
And then at the very end, once more... Why?
どうやってさ、スキップできる？スキップ？
Why can you skip like that? Skip?
まつりちゃん、スキップガバガバなんだけどさ。
Matsuri-chan, your skips are all over the place!
そうだな、ペンギンみたいになる。
That's right, like a penguin.
昨日、そう、スキップできないからふぶちゃんのスキップをおじちゃんみたいな。
Yesterday, you couldn't skip, so I want to see Fubuki's skip!
スキップ。
Skip.
うん、その場スキップかな。
Skip right on the spot!
ぶんぶんめちゃくちゃできるよ。
You can skip quite a lot!
かわいい！待って待って、そのぐるぐる回って、スキップでぐるぐる回って。
Cute! Wait, wait, spin around with a skip.
るんるんする。
Do it like this!
「うれしいな」「うれしいな」って！
Saying "I'm so happy" over and over!
え、かわっ、ははっ！
Eh, cute! Haha!
は？は？は？って何だよ。
What? What? What is that?
なべぐさぽにてーるがさ、ちょう...そうそうそうそう、めちゃめちゃいいな。
Nabe-gusa's ponytail is... yes, yes, yes, super good!
1回転して、くるって、くるって1回転して、「みんな」って言って。
Do a full 360-degree spin, and say "everyone!"
みんなーーー！ははっ！
Everyone! Haha!
かわいい。
So cute!
かわいい、すごい、うまいこと...うん、すれ...
So cute, amazing, so skillful!
なんで、なんで今日そこにいないんだろ、私。なんで、ねえ、みこちゃん我々空の上からね、声かけてんだろう。
Why aren't you there today? Why, Miko-chan, are you calling us from above the sky?
でも、これねこわかるんだけど、これその場にあの、ふぶちゃんいたらたぶん死んでんだ。
For me, I get it, but if Fubu-chan was there, she'd probably be dead.
死んだ！そうだな、たぶん、あの恥骨骨折してるわ。よかった今日画面ね。
Dead! That's right, she'd probably fracture her tailbone! Good thing you weren't on screen today!
ふぶせんぱいは今度すんのな？ろがてん、おがんだん！うむ。
Fubu-senpai is going to do it next time! Rogatan, ogan-tan! Uh-huh!
まあ、ということでじゃ、この後もうん。
Well then, let's work hard for this part too!
しっかり頑張ってふくれ！ありがと...頑張ってね、ふくれあ！本当、ありがとうございます！
Work hard! Thank you very much!
パラバラ、パラバラ！ありがとーーー！がんばってーーー！はーい！
Parabara, parabara, thank you! Work hard! Yes!
だね、すごい先輩たちが来てくれて、本当にありがとうございました！
So, the senior members came to see us, truly thank you very much!
あの、活発な先輩たちからも元気もらったんで、次はですね、ちょっと雰囲気が変わっていくんですけど、歌のね...
We got energy from the active senior members, so next up...
ステージじゃないんですけど、歌に行こうかなって思うんですよ。まあちょっと1回挟みたいんですけど。
Not the stage, but I think we should go to the songs. Let's take a break first though.
じゃあちょっと一旦移動します！えー、ライブステージに、GO！
So let's move for a bit. To the live stage, go!
あ、ちゃんと移動した！
Oh, it moved properly!
今日はもうダメだ、スタッフさん今日移動できないんじゃないかとと思ってた。
Today, I thought staff members wouldn't even be able to move today!
なんとかいけました！
Somehow we made it!
えー、ではですね、今日まず、あの...こっからは歌のパートになるんですけど、
So today, first, from here it'll be the song part, but...
ちょっとまあ、あの、みんなにね、私もお手紙書いてきたから、その前に読んでもいいかな、なんか。
Before that, I got letters from everyone, so before reading them...
もし仮にね、いや泣くようなこと書いてねえんだけど、もし仮に泣いちゃったらちょっと、あの、歌えなくなっちゃうな、そん...
If by any chance... well, I didn't write anything that would make you cry, but if by any chance you start crying, it might make the singing stop... so...
ね、ちょっとう、歌の前に お手紙を読みたいなと思います。
So, I want to read my letter before the songs.
ちょっと、お手紙どこだっけ？
Wait, where is my letter?
お手紙、読ませてもろて。
Let me read my letter.
えー、エルフレのみんなへ。よーお！お待たせ！待ったな？
To everyone in Elf-R: Yo! Kept you waiting, did I?
えっと、応援してくれていたみんなも、最近始めたみんなも、いつも本当にありがとうございます。
To everyone who has been cheering me on, and everyone who started supporting me recently, thank you allways so much!
みんなにはいつも心配をかけてしまっているような気がしています。
I feel like I'm always making you worry.
私が「心配しないで」って言っても心配してくれる優しいみんなが大好きです。
Even when I say "Don't worry," I love everyone who worries for me because you're so kind!
私はすごく不器用で、自分の思うようにいかなくて悔しいなっていう気持ちになったこともたくさんありました。
I'm very clumsy and often feel frustrated that I can't do things the way I want.
それでもみんなが支えてくれたから頑張れたって思います。
Even so, I feel like I was able to do my best because everyone supported me.
どんなことがあっても、最後は...
No matter what happens, in the end...
どんなことがあっても、最後は笑って「そんなこともあったね」って
No matter what happens, in the end, to be able to smile and say,
言えるようにこれからもたくさん頑張るので、
"We had times like that too"—
私のことをこれからも支えてくれたら嬉しいなって思います。
I'll keep working hard so I can say that, and I'd be happy if you continue to support me.
みんな大好きだよ！
I love you all!
そして、えー私の、お父さん。
And, um, my dad.
お父さんへ、え、いつもなんだかんだ言ってくれるとかね。
To my dad, um, you always give me your opinions and stuff.
え、たくさんわがまま聞いてくれてありがとう。え、これからもきっと心配かけちゃうこともあるかもしれないんだけど、可愛がってくれるお父さんの娘としてとっても嬉しいし大好きです。
Thanks for listening to all my selfishness. Um, I might still cause you to worry from time to time, but as the daughter of such a loving dad, I'm so happy and I love you.
お仕事大変だけど、大変だと思うけど、無理しないでね。あの、席ろほどほどにね。
Work is tough, I know it's tough, but don't overdo it. You know, take it easy on the alcohol.
てことで、これからもよろしくね。
So, thanks for your continued support.
ここにはね、書いてない。あの、お手紙これしかないんですけど、あの、このライブのみんなも本当にいつもありがとうございます。
It's not written here, this letter is all I have, but, um, to everyone in this live stream, thank you so much, as always.
いつも遊んでくれたり、気にかけてくれたり、ありがとうございます。
Thank you for always hanging out with me and looking out for me.
スタッフのみんなも、マネージャーさんの、皆さんも本当にいつもありがとうございます。これからもよろしくお願いします。
To all the staff, managers, and everyone, thank you truly as always. I look forward to working with you all.
それから、え、3期生のみんな。お前らには特に何もねえわ。(笑)
And then, um, everyone in Gen 3. You guys especially get nothing! Haha.
これからもよろしくな、大好きだ。
Thanks for everything moving forward, I love you guys.
ってことでですね、お手紙以上です。危ねえ危ねえ、泣きそうになったがなんとかこらえた。
So, that's the end of the letter. Phew, close one, I almost cried but managed to hold it in.
まあね、そんな大好きな仲間たちと、ちょっと1曲歌ってから、あの、歌パートに行こうかなって思います。
Well, with such beloved friends, I think I'll sing a song before heading over to the singing part.
あ、そう、その前にね、ちょっと、その前に私忘れてた。あの、告知してもいいかな？
Ah, right, before that, wait, I forgot before that. Can I make an announcement?
あの、明日ですね、20時30分に「愛言葉Ⅲ」こちら歌ってみた公開しますので、プレミア公開だからよかったらみんな見てください。絶対見てね！
Um, tomorrow at 20:30, I'll be releasing a cover of 'Ai Kotoba III,' so it's a premiere, please come watch if you'd like. Be sure to watch!
はい。ぜひぜひよろしくお願いしますね。絶対見てくれ、これすごく頑張ったんだ。みんなに感謝の気持ちと愛を込めて伝わったら嬉しいなって思います。
Yes. Please look forward to it. Definitely watch it, I worked really hard on this. I hope my gratitude and love reach everyone.
はい、ではですね、ここからは、え、元気い3期生のみんなと歌おうかなって思います。
Alright, then from here, um, I think I'll sing cheerfully with everyone in Gen 3.
はい！えーい！わーい！
Yay! Hey! Woohoo!
ちょっと泣きそうになったぺこだよ。
I almost cried there, Peko.
これからもよろしくなで？
Thanks for your continued support, right?
いやなんか最後と愛してる、よろしくねって全然伝わんねえが。
Wait, 'at the end I love you, thanks for everything' didn't come across at all!
いやでもね、せっちゃんはあの、この前よの、なんか、空気感というか空気感っていうか、取ってる時が一番、ぐっときて、
Well, you know, Setchan, um, the other day, that kind of vibe, or rather when I was recording it, it hit me the hardest,
なんか自分がはしゃいでる時は、ぐって盛り上がっててたんだけど、
like when I was having fun and getting pumped up,
一旦落ち着くとね
once things calm down...
あ、泣いてるなって。よかったね。
Ah, she's crying. Good for you.
うん。で、今日ね、ノエル？ちょっと待って、何が、もう何言ってるかわかりませんて。ごめんね、大丈夫。で、今度、本当ね、隣でね、ちょっとちょっと言って、あ、大丈夫か、もうちょっと、もうちょっと出てきてくださそ、もうちょっとぺこだよ。
Yeah. And today, Noel? Wait, what, I don't even know what I'm saying. Sorry, it's okay. Next time, really, right next to me, whispering a bit—ah, is it okay? A little more—Come out a little more, Peko. A little more Peko.
大丈夫か、ノエルに貰い泣きしてちょっと泣きそうになってしまっているが (笑)。歌わせるから、ちょ、私のハンカチ取って。
Are you okay? You caught Noel's crying, and now you're about to cry too. Haha. Make me sing, hey, grab my handkerchief.
私のノエルから貰ったハンカチを取ってもらって、あ、オソロのやつね。3期生のオソロの。
Grab the handkerchief I got from Noel. Ah, the matching one. The Gen 3 matching one.
泣い、泣い、泣い！
Cry, cry, cry!
顔赤いよ、ふりあ、歌う、歌うよ、みんなで。
Your face is so red, Furia. Let's sing, let's sing together everyone.
うん。歌う。元気に歌って、何だ何だ？早く帰るだよ！わかった、じゃあ、
Yeah. Sing. Sing cheerfully, what's with that? Go home early! Okay, then,
え、みんなで盛り上がるぞ！ミュージック、スタート！
everyone, let's get hyped! Music, start!
なんてぺこらなんだ。いやお前ららしいだろ。(笑) 3期生感ね。
What a Pekora thing to do. Well, that's typical of you guys. Haha. That Gen 3 vibe.
ワンナイト・カーニバル 胸の奥 zuki-zukiと音立ててる Angel
One Night Carnival, my heart's beating so loud, angel.
とにかくもう行儀良くて真面目になんてうんざりだった Angel
Anyway, I was sick of being serious and well-mannered, angel.
退屈に怯えてたのさ 夜の闇に逃げ込んだ Angel
Scared of boredom, we ran into the night, angel.
俺達まるで捨て猫みたいな 俺達に帰る場所なんてもうどこにもなかった Angel
Like stray cats, we no longer had a place to call home, angel.
Can you master baby? master baby!
Can't you master baby? master baby!
Can you master baby? be my baby!!
Can't you master baby? so long...
瞬きもせずに 私たちは光の渦に巻き込まれていく
Without blinking, we're sucked into a swirling light.
雲の間に間に 照らせ 青白き月よ 照らせ
Shine in between the clouds, shine on, blue-white moon.
星が瞬く distance さみしがり屋達の伝説さ
The stars twinkle in the distance, we're legendary loners.
One Night Carnival fun fun
Can you master baby? master baby!
Can't you master baby? master baby!
まばたきもせずに
Without blinking,
俺たちは光の渦に巻き込まれていく
we are sucked into a whirlpool of light.
雲の隙間に 照らせ 青白き月よ 照らせ
Shine in between the clouds, shine on, blue-white moon!
星が瞬く distance さみしがり屋達の伝説さ
Stars twinkle in the distance, we're legendary loners.
風に香る tactics が 俺の胸を締め付ける
The fragrance of tactics on the wind makes my heart clench.
「今だけは悲しい嘘聴きたくないよ」
"I don't want to hear any sad lies right now."
one night carnival fun fun
まり、聞いたことないのに良く頑張って覚えてくれたね。
Mari, you worked hard to learn it even though you'd never heard it before.
一時間で覚えたで...
You learned it in an hour?
一番ね、詳しそうなのに初めて聞いたず...
You look like you'd know it best, but you heard it for the first time?
ちょっとアニメソングしか知らなくて...
I only know anime songs...
や、なんか、あの、パンク系ってほらホストとかさやるじゃん。
Well, you know, punk style, hosts and stuff do that.
なんかその時からね、チャラけてるから、
From back then, they were all playful,
明るくしてききたかったの、この後ね結構シリアスな曲とか、
and I wanted to make it bright! After this, we have some serious
かっこいい曲とかを、あの、取り揃えておりますので、
and cool songs lined up,
その前にね、なんかシリアスにして私ちょっとさっき泣き泣いちゃったから、
so before that, since I was a bit serious and crying earlier,
あの声震えて歌えなくなるから、あ、ちょっと盛り上げちゃってね、
my voice would shake and I wouldn't be able to sing, so we hyped it up
ノートの調整をね。そうなの
to adjust the notes. Right.
ルーちゃんも見ててね。
Lou-chan, watch too.
ごめん、話してないからねもうね。
Sorry, I haven't been talking, right?
みんなも見ててね、ちゃんと。なんか
Everyone watch properly too. Like...
三期生だけじゃなくて、みんなも見ててね、もう。
not just the 3rd gen, everyone watch too.
お前らも停滞の中の1人だぞって話よ。
You guys are part of the stagnation too, that's what I'm saying.
ノエル大丈夫? 金欠ピコなんですよ。
Noel, are you okay? I'm broke right now.
じゃあね、えー歌、歌パート3曲用意したので、歌っていきたいと思います。
Well then, um, I've prepared 3 songs for the singing part, so I'd like to sing them.
じゃあ1曲目行きたいと思います、聞いてください、「ナイトメア」。
Now for the 1st song, please listen to "Nightmare".
嫌んなっちまったぜ なぁ
I'm so sick of it, hey,
振り返りゃくんないし
you won't even look back.
既読がついた LINE
LINE with a read receipt
放置プレイ 2日もそのままで
left ignored for two days.
「現在は仕事モードだから恋愛はちょっと…」
"I'm in work mode right now, so romance is a bit..."
都合のいい断り文句が痛いや
Those convenient excuses hurt.
8mg の煙草と吐き悶えたロン缶ハイボール
An 8mg cigarette and a messy long-can highball,
悪酔いの果て こぼれた君の NAME
my drunkenness spilling your name.
胸騒ぎな Night は冷たい
My uneasy night is cold,
鼻の奥がツンとしちまうのは
why does the back of my nose tingle?
Wake up in a Nightmare 寒さのせいだけかな
Wake up in a Nightmare, is it just because of the cold?
頬を撫でた夜風は
The night breeze stroking my cheek
君の黒い髪のように
is like your black hair.
Wake up in a Nightmare
オリオンが霞む 夢見心地な日々は
Orion blurs, these dreamy days
君がかえた幻影か
are they an illusion you cast?
恋の魔物のあざ笑う声が響く
The mocking laughter of love's monster echoes.
狂い出す歯車 どこまでが夢なんだ?
Gears spinning out of control, where does the dream end?
何もかもがまばたきだったのか?
Was everything just a blink?
胸騒ぎな Night に溶けたい
I want to melt into this uneasy night,
冷たいアスファルト 革ジャン越し
through the cold asphalt and leather jacket.
Wake up in a Nightmare
走馬灯 君との記憶
Revolving lantern, memories with you.
矢で射らる僕は何て
Shot by an arrow, what am I...
天にあげられることなんてない
There's nothing to give up to heaven.
Wake up in a Nightmare オリオンは見えない
Wake up in a Nightmare, Orion can't be seen.
嫌んなっちまったぜ なぁ
I'm so sick of it, hey,
悪い夢見てんだよ
I'm just having a bad dream.
やさぐれた Night 忘れたい
A rough night I want to forget,
腫れのひかない瞼開くんだ
opening my swollen eyelids.
Wake up in a Nightmare
惨めに明るむ空 口の中残った煙い臭い
A miserably brightening sky, the smokey smell in my mouth,
また虚しいのさ
so hollow again.
Wake up in a Nightmare
オリオンは南へ
Orion heads south.
浮世は闇 艶を求め彷徨い
Floating world is darkness, wandering in search of allure
辿り着く 欲塗れの浄土
Arriving at a pure land smeared with greed
菩薩の顔返せば 鬼の扉
If you turn back the Bodhisattva's face, it's a demon's door
知らぬ間に飲み込まれたら
If you get swallowed up before you know it
らんらん らんらん 針の簪で 回転マイム
La-la, la-la, rotating mime with a needle hairpin
落ちる天 笑うキミ
Falling heaven, laughing you
絶頂クラッカー 言葉なんてもう要らないね
Climax cracker, words are no longer needed
それは世にも奇妙な泡沫の夢 踊り狂ってる 偶像lover
That is a bizarre bubble dream in this world, dancing wildly, idol lover
ドラマティック 淫婦さながら 乱れた吐息 funny motion
Dramatic, like a wanton woman, disordered breath, funny motion
感情淘汰 泡沫の夢
Emotional elimination, bubble dream
故意に恋してる 盲目lover
Intentionally in love, blind lover
弾き飛んだ愛がギラギラ
The blown-off love is glaringly bright
極彩色のア buggy dance hall
A colorful buggy dance hall
ようこそ 世界の果て へ
Welcome to the edge of the world
魔法が 解け 目覚めれば そこ は 底 で
When the magic breaks and you wake up, that place is at the bottom
届かない 叫びが 響いた
The unreachable cry echoed
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
はい、ナイトメアでしたー！
Yes, that was NightMaRe!
ちょっと、次の曲歌う前にさ、あの、お水飲んでいい？
Before I sing the next song, um, can I drink some water?
なんかでもね、始まる前のほうがすごく緊張してて、歌い始めたらね、
Before it started I was so nervous, but once I started singing,
そんなに緊張してなくなった。みんなのおかげかもしれんね。
I wasn't as nervous anymore. Maybe it's thanks to everyone.
よし、次の曲に行こうと思うよ。
Alright, I think I'll move on to the next song.
次の曲、えー、行きたいと思います。君がいるなら。
The next song, um, I'd like to go to. If You Are Here.
初めて出会ったその日から
Ever since the day we first met,
重ねた言葉の数だけ
just by the number of words we've piled up,
気づけばこの手に溢れてる
before I knew it, it's overflowing in these hands.
伝えたい想いがある
There are feelings I want to convey.
不意に弱さを見せるたび 僕らが強くなれるのは
Every time I show my sudden weakness, what allows us to grow stronger
両手を広げて受け止めてくれる人がいるから
is because there is someone who opens their arms and accepts us.
君と語り合ったあの夢の景色は まだ見えないけど
The scenery of that dream we talked about with you is still invisible, but
見守ってほしいんだ いつかたどり着くその時まで
I want you to watch over me until the day we finally reach it.
君がいるなら そばにいるなら
If you are here, if you are by my side,
どんな遠い未来でも
no matter how distant the future may be,
信じてゆける 歩いてゆける
I can keep believing, I can keep walking.
この背中を押してくれる
Someone who pushes this back of mine—
ひとりじゃないと思えることが
being able to feel that I'm not alone
力になるから 生きてゆくこと
gives me strength, so living life
楽じゃなくても 乗り越えてゆけるとそう思うよ
isn't easy, but I think I can overcome it.
素直になれないことも 心をぶつけ合うこともある
There are times when I can't be honest, and times when our hearts clash,
それでも一緒にいたいのは 終わらない絆があるから
yet the reason I still want to be together is because we have an unbreakable bond.
風に吹かれても 長い雨に振られても
Even if blown by the wind, even if beaten by long rains,
ただ前を見て そうしてゆくんだ
I just look ahead and keep going like that,
いつか夢が叶うその日まで
until the day our dreams finally come true.
色とりどりの願いを込めて
Pouring in multicolored wishes,
また輝く未来を描いてゆく 作ってゆく
I keep drawing and creating a shining future once more.
手を取り合った僕らなら
If it's us holding hands together...
それが甘すぎる日々でも やっとの思いで 今日を開けて
Even in those overly sweet days, with much effort, I opened up today.
もっと大事にしたいと 誓った場所の
The start of the morning at the place where I swore to cherish it more—
始まりの朝を いまだって 覚えているんだ
I still remember it even now.
君がいるなら そばにいるなら
If you are here, if you are by my side,
愛の 欠けた世界でも
even in a world devoid of love,
信じて進める 歩いていける
I can believe and press forward, I can keep walking.
こんな背中を 押してくれる 一人ひとりの
Carrying the wishes of each and every person who pushes this back of mine—
願いを乗せて
carrying their wishes.
いま 変わりゆく時代を 支えている 笑って生きている
Right now, supporting a changing era, living with a smile—
僕らなら できると思うよ
I believe we can do it.
君がいるなら そばにいるなら それだけで強くなれるよ
If you are here, if you are by my side, that alone can make me strong.
はい、えーっと、ありがとうございます！
Yes, um, thank you so much!
もう残すところあと1曲になりました。
We're already down to our last song.
皆さん、いかがだったでしょうか？楽しんでいただけたかな？
How was it, everyone? Did you all have fun?
で、最後まで、これ…これみんな、うずらないで！いっぱいツイートしてね！
And please... don't slack off until the very end! Tweet a lot, okay?
まだまだ、最後まで楽しんでってほしいなって思うからね。
Because I want you to enjoy yourselves right up until the very end.
最後…なんか、のえるちゃんは…
At the very end... Noel-chan...
私の代わりにのえるが泣いてくれたということで。
Noel cried in my place, so...
最後はリクエストも多かったし、私も歌いたかった曲を歌いたいと思います。
For the last song, since we got many requests and it's a song I wanted to sing too,
最後この曲を歌ったら、そのままとお別れしたいと思います。皆さん本当にありがとうございました！
Once I sing this song, I'll be saying goodbye. Thank you all so very much!
最後まで盛り上がっていきましょう！
Let's get hyped right to the end!
では、最後の曲いきたいと思います。
Now, let's move on to the final song.
教室モノクローム
Classroom Monochrome
まだ見ぬ本当の自分のことが
The truth about myself, which I still haven't seen,
自分自身でも分からなくて
I don't even understand myself,
誰かに手を差し伸べてもらって
and having someone reach out a hand to me—
痛みとは違った痛みを 知る
I'm learning a pain different from sorrow.
モノクロームの未来予想図
A monochrome future blueprint,
絵の具を探して
searching for paints.
でも今は なぜだろう なぜだろう 色づくよ
But right now, why is it, why is it starting to color?
ゆっくりと 花が道に誇って咲くみたいに
Slowly, like flowers blooming proudly along the path,
放課後のチャイムに 待ち焦がれた風が吹き抜けてる
the long-awaited wind blows through the after-school chime.
感じたことのない居心地の良さに まだ戸惑ってるよ
I'm still bewildered by this comfort I've never felt before.
こんな温かいと 笑顔がね 隠せない
It's so warm that I can't hide my smile.
なぜだろう 大丈夫だよって言葉 教科書のどこにも乗ってなくてさ
Why is it? Phrases like "it's going to be alright" aren't written anywhere in textbooks.
あの時どうしたらよかったのか
What should I have done back then?
夢を半分こした 今ならわかるよ
Now I understand, having shared our dreams halfway.
信じるってこと大切もの やっと見つけられた
I've finally found what it means to believe, something so precious.
だから行く 日だまりと温もりと 厳しさもつながりも 全部 全部 くれた場所
That's why I'm going—to the place that gave me everything: sunlight, warmth, strictness, and connections.
廊下で蝶が羽ばたいて
In the hallway, a butterfly fluttered its wings,
グランドに嵐が起きた
and a storm arose on the grounds.
知らぬ奴に絡まれても
Even when pestered by strangers,
適当にあしらえぬ自己顕示
I can't brush off my desire for attention.
理科準備室の片隅で
In a corner of the science prep room,
雄雌雄雌こんにちわ
hello to males and females alike.
気遣い気付かれ傷ついて
Being considerate, noticed, and hurt,
もう前頭葉から花が咲く
flowers are already blooming from my frontal lobe.
ねぇ、私似合ってたかな
Hey, did this suit me?
友達ってできたかな
Did I make friends?
会えなくてもいいかな
Can I be okay even if we can't meet?
許してもらえるのかな
Will you forgive me?
あたしはあたしの
As for me, my...
精一杯 精一杯 心から心から
with all my heart, from the bottom of my heart,
あるがままに歌ってもいいのかな
is it okay to sing just as I am?
射す光が眩しかった
The shining light was dazzling.
雪解けのように流れてた
Flowing like melting snow,
涙があふれて止まらないよ
tears overflow and won't stop.
こんな こんな 温かいんだ
How warm this is,
あたしの帰る場所
my place to return to.
My place to return to.
皆様、ありがとうございました！
Thank you everyone!
皆これからもよろしくね！
Please keep supporting me from now on too!